export const chapter = "Chapter - 6: The Coastal : Plains and Islands  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What are the plains along the shores of the Arabian Sea called?",
        optionA: "Eastern Coastal Plains",
        optionB: "Western Coastal Plains",
        optionC: "Southern Coastal Plains",
        correctAnswer: "Western Coastal Plains",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region in the Western Coastal Plains is famous for the Gir National Park?",
        optionA: "The Gujarat Coast",
        optionB: "The Konkan Coast",
        optionC: "The Malabar Coast",
        correctAnswer: "The Gujarat Coast",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which part of the Eastern Coastal Plains is famous for its lagoons and backwaters?",
        optionA: "The Northern Circars",
        optionB: "The Coromandel Coast",
        optionC: "The Gujarat Coast",
        correctAnswer: "The Malabar Coast",
      },
      {
        question: "Which islands are located in the Bay of Bengal?",
        optionA: "Andaman and Nicobar Islands",
        optionB: "Lakshadweep Islands",
        optionC: "Maldives",
        correctAnswer: "Andaman and Nicobar Islands",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of the region in the Eastern Coastal Plains known for its fertile soil due to river deltas?",
        optionA: "The Northern Circars",
        optionB: "The Coromandel Coast",
        optionC: "The Gujarat Coast",
        correctAnswer: "The Coromandel Coast",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which island group is known for being built of coral deposits?",
        optionA: "Andaman and Nicobar Islands",
        optionB: "Lakshadweep Islands",
        optionC: "Maldives",
        correctAnswer: "Lakshadweep Islands",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the southernmost part of India?",
        optionA: "Kanyakumari",
        optionB: "Indira Point",
        optionC: "Chennai",
        correctAnswer: "Indira Point",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which coast is rocky and uneven, with lighthouses to warn ships against rocks?",
        optionA: "The Gujarat Coast",
        optionB: "The Konkan Coast",
        optionC: "The Malabar Coast",
        correctAnswer: "The Konkan Coast",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the width of the Western Coastal Plains in the narrowest areas?",
        optionA: "10 km",
        optionB: "50 km",
        optionC: "80 km",
        correctAnswer: "10 km",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which coastal plains have deltas of the Mahanadi, Godavari, Krishna, and Kaveri rivers?",
        optionA: "Western Coastal Plains",
        optionB: "Eastern Coastal Plains",
        optionC: "Southern Coastal Plains",
        correctAnswer: "Eastern Coastal Plains",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The plains along the shores of the Arabian Sea are called __________ Coastal Plains.",
        optionA: "Western",
        optionB: "Eastern",
        optionC: "Southern",
        correctAnswer: "Western",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Western Coastal Plains extend from Gujarat in the north and pass through Maharashtra, Goa, Karnataka, and Kerala. They are narrower in Karnataka and broader in Kerala. They are made up of alluvial soil brought down by the short streams originating from the Western Ghats. These plains are divided into three main parts: 1. The Gujarat Coast in the north, 2. The Konkan Coast in the middle, and 3. The __________ Coast in the south.",
        optionA: "Eastern",
        optionB: "Malabar",
        optionC: "Southern",
        correctAnswer: "Malabar",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The coast along the state of Gujarat is called the Gujarat Coast. The famous Gulf of Kutch and Gulf of Khambhat are located in this coast. The famous Gir National Park is also located here. The region of Gujarat Coast is known for its __________.",
        optionA: "Deserts",
        optionB: "Forests",
        optionC: "Wildlife",
        correctAnswer: "Wildlife",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Konkan Coast stretches from the coast of Maharashtra to Goa. The land of this region is rocky and uneven. The rocks run right into the ocean, due to which there is a danger for the ships running aground. Therefore, a number of lighthouses have been built along the coast to warn the ships and boats against rocks in the water. This region is known for its rocky terrain and the presence of __________ along the coast.",
        optionA: "Jungles",
        optionB: "Lighthouses",
        optionC: "Fishing villages",
        correctAnswer: "Lighthouses",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Malabar Coast stretches from Goa to Kanyakumari. It is famous for its lagoons. Lagoons are areas of shallow water separated from the sea by sand bars. These lagoons are also called backwaters of the sea. They are connected with one another by canals. These lagoons are used for navigation by boats and steamers. The Malabar Coast is famous for its beautiful __________ and waterways.",
        optionA: "Beaches",
        optionB: "Coral reefs",
        optionC: "Islands",
        correctAnswer: "Beaches",
      },
      {
        question:
          "On the east, between the Eastern Ghats and the Bay of Bengal, are the Eastern Coastal Plains. They begin from West Bengal in the north, and pass through Odisha, Andhra Pradesh, Telangana, and Tamil Nadu. The Eastern Coastal Plains are wider than the Western Coastal Plains. The plains stretch for nearly 1500 km with nearly a width of 100 km. The deltas of the Mahanadi, Godavari, Krishna, and Kaveri rivers have formed nearly 25% of the area of this plain. The soil of the deltas is very fertile. We can divide these plains into two parts: 1. The Northern Circars in the north and 2. The __________ Coast in the south.",
        optionA: "Coromandel",
        optionB: "Gujarat",
        optionC: "Konkan",
        correctAnswer: "Coromandel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The northern parts of the Eastern Coastal Plains are called the Northern Circars. The region stretches up to the coast of West Bengal to the coast of Odisha and Andhra Pradesh. Visakhapatnam is an important seaport of the Northern Circars. The southern part of the Eastern Coastal Plains is known as the Coromandel Coast and covers the coast of Tamil Nadu. Chennai is the major port of this coastline. It is the third-largest port in India. What is the major port of the Northern Circars?",
        optionA: "Chennai",
        optionB: "Visakhapatnam",
        optionC: "Mumbai",
        correctAnswer: "Visakhapatnam",
      },
      {
        question:
          "There are two major island groups in Indiaâ€”the Andaman and Nicobar Islands in the Bay of Bengal and the Lakshadweep Islands in the Arabian Sea. The Andaman Islands are separated from the Nicobar Islands by a water body called the __________.",
        optionA: "Arabian Channel",
        optionB: "Ten Degree Channel",
        optionC: "Andaman Passage",
        correctAnswer: "Ten Degree Channel",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Andaman and Nicobar Islands are believed to be an elevated portion of submarine mountains. Some smaller islands in this group are volcanic in origin, with the only active volcano in India, known as __________, situated in the Nicobar Islands.",
        optionA: "Barren Island",
        optionB: "Andaman Island",
        optionC: "Volcano Island",
        correctAnswer: "Barren Island",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Lakshadweep Islands are located at a distance of 280 km-480 km off the Malabar Coast. The entire group of islands is built of coral deposits, so they are also called __________.",
        optionA: "Volcanic islands",
        optionB: "Atolls",
        optionC: "Archipelagos",
        correctAnswer: "Atolls",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Western Coastal Plains extend from Gujarat in the north to Kerala in the south.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "The Malabar Coast is known for its rocky terrain.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The Konkan Coast is famous for its lagoons and backwaters.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Andaman Islands are separated from the Nicobar Islands by the Arabian Sea.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Northern Circars are the southern part of the Eastern Coastal Plains.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Lakshadweep Islands are built of volcanic deposits.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The National Emblem of India consists of three Asiatic lions.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The National Anthem of India was originally composed in Bengali.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "The Peacock is the National Bird of India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Bengal Tiger was declared the National Animal of India in 1963.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
